XIN ZHANG

Personal website amanda4zx.github.io LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/xin-zhang-amanda

Research Interest

My research interest is in the intersection of security, formal verification and programming languages. I hope to formally verify well-defined security properties of real-life programs, ideally binary code, so programmers implementing cryptographic protocols can be confident that the resulting code achieves the security specifications, and users can be assured that the executable files they download do what they claim to do and nothing more. I believe in the power of security by design, and programming language theories, backed by rigorous mathematical foundations, is a promising way towards the goal. I hope to study how to design programming languages that are expressive enough for specific domains and produce compiled results that are amenable to computer-aided formal verification.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science

2019 - 2022

University of Oxford, United Kingdom First Class Honours Cohort ranking: 1/43

Research Experience

Research Engineer in Cybersecurity

2022 - Present

Agency for Science, Technology and Research, Singapore

I am working on a project with the objective of improving a homomorphic encryption compiler in terms of functionality and performance; I am also joining a project that uses formal verification to verify security properties of cryptographic schemes.

Final-Year Project in Robustness Evaluation of Attention Neural Networks

2021 - 2022

University of Oxford, United Kingdom

I trained neural network models with attention mechanisms based on existing literature and evaluated their robustness. I found evidence suggesting that attention neural networks for image classification may not be more robust than models without attention mechanisms.

Summer Attachment in Lattice-Based Cryptography

2021

Agency for Science, Technology and Research, Singapore

I learnt about the underlying mathematical problems of lattice-based cryptography, studied a paper on a lattice signatures and gave a presentation about the paper.

Research attachment in Computational Biology

2017 - 2018

Agency for Science, Technology and Research, Singapore

I designed and conducted experiments to collect electroencephalogram (EEG) signals of subjects while they perform mental arithmetic, and I trained a machine learning model to distinguish mental arithmetic difficulty levels based on the EEG signals.

Achievements and Awards

National Science Scholarship (BS-PhD)

2019 - Present

Awarded by Agency for Science, Technology and Research, Singapore

Hoare's Prize 2022

For the best overall performance in Computer Science 2022

Awarded by Department of Computer Science, University of Oxford, United Kingdom

Book Prizes 2020, 2021

For two first-class vacation essays and performance in a few assessments Awarded by St Catherine's College, University of Oxford, United Kingdom

College Scholarship 2020

For the performance in the end-of-year assessments in Computer Science Awarded by St Catherine's College, University of Oxford, United Kingdom

Silver Award 2018

For the paper and the poster presentation at Singapore Science and Engineering Fair 2018

Publications

- Chao Jin, Khin Mi Mi Aung, Xin Zhang. Secure Collaborative Design of Experiments with Homomorphic Encryption. Proceedings of the 5th Homomorphic Encryption.org Standards Workshop. September 2022.
- Zheng Yang Chin, Xin Zhang, Chuanchu Wang, Kai Keng Ang. *EEG-based discrimination of different cognitive workload levels from mental arithmetic.* Proceedings of the 40th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC). July 2018.
- Xin Zhang, Zheng Yang Chin, Kai Keng Ang. Assessing user cognitive workload from changes in electroencephalogram elicited during mental arithmetic. Proceedings of the Singapore Science and Engineering Fair 2018. April 2018.